Shivam Sood

Full Stack Software Developer

Mississauga, ON, L5B4M1 ★ (647) 936-8241 shivam183@outlook.com ★ www.linkedin.com/in/ssood1

Quality-driven and resourceful software developer with diverse experience delivering best quality software products in line with business / project requirements. Demonstrated excellence in backend as well as front-end web development. Hands on experience with various programming languages, including C# and Angular. Proven history across agile environments while collaborating with business analysis and tech teams to define core requirements, application designs, architecture patterns, and technology strategy. Trusted and admired by the leadership for successful, on-time, and under-budget project deliveries through implementation of Agile practices and regular sprint sessions.

Technical Proficiencies

Languages & Tools: C#, Angular, CSS3, NodeJS, Angular10, Typescript, JavaScript, React, TypeScript, HTML5, Bootstrap, REST,

Express, ORM, NPM, JWT, AJAX, Chai, Mocha, ¡Query, ASP.NET Core, NUnit, Jasmine, Karma.

Database & Cloud: MongoDB Atlas, MSSQL, Oracle, MySQL, JDBC, SQLite, Database 12c, AWS, Heroku.

IDE & Tools: GIT, Visual Studio / Visual Studio Code, Postman, SoapUI, InteIIiJ, Eclipse, Android Studio, Visual Paradigm.

Professional Experience

Software Developer, Symbility Solutions (CoreLogic), Toronto, ON

Feb 2021 - Present

Review existing Insurance application, outline key areas of improvement, and implement modifications to the application to include new features and enhance application performance. Facilitate peer developers by conducting Code Reviews and leveraging technical expertise. Act as occasional sprint master as well as organize daily standups, bi-weekly planning, and surveys to ensure adherence to project requirements and deliverables. Oversee front and back-end to Database development of the respective project (LINK 2.0). Support professional / talent development by educating new hires on software development process.

- Optimized existing Insurance application by including new features for time zone abbreviation support.
- ♦ Modified and upgraded old Insured AngularJS app to new Angular 11 (LINK 2.0).
- ♦ Customized application and added functionality of chat integration, custom brandings to LINK 2.0.
- Implemented Mobile first approach and integrated support for all device sizes including smartphones, tablets, and desktops.

Software Developer, LoadLink Technologies, Mississauga, ON

Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

Upgraded Link Dispatch Flagship product from old Windows form (.net MVC/C#) to Angular 10 and .NET Core API application, along with managing various frontend development activities for Angular. Studied client requirements to generate architectural designs for angular frontend. Conducted integrations with third-party libraries, including ag-grid, angular material, chart.Js, and API.

- ♦ Enabled 75%+ code coverage and 90+ unit tests by utilizing Jasmine and Karma.
- ♦ Championed new product launch that increased subscriptions by 10% and decreased customer production errors by 15%.
- ♦ Applied agile methodologies with Bi-weekly sprints and regular standups as well as implemented Azure DevOps with CI/CD pipeline integrations resulting in smooth project development and delivery.

Software Developer, BELL CANADA, Mississauga, ON

July 2019 - July 2020

Procured and addressed software and application development needs of other departments in collaboration with software team. Coordinated with hardware team to manage inventory, address UPS Battery Tracking system issues, and improve HR Recruiting app. Applied automation scripts and HTML / JSON Parsers to ensure effective data collection and cleaning.

- ♦ Introduced new features in eBay app that ensured better accessibility and functionality.
- Created full stack software for GIS team members that automated geocoding process and saved time.

Education